All right, let's get going.
Good morning, everyone.
I'm Pablo.
I work in the Foundry IQ team.
And what what we'll do in this session is talk
about what it takes to connect agents and your AI
models with the knowledge that makes them connect to your
applications, to your company and to the data they need
to get their job done.
So you're cutting to the chase.
Foundry IQ is the thing you use to connect agents
to knowledge.
Now when we think about Foundry IQ, we think about
getting this done in with three fundamental elements in consideration.
First, we want it to be piece of cake to
get started.
Second, we want versatility so that as your application gets
sophisticated, your needs grow or the problems get hard, you
have what you need right in the same platform.
And 3rd, like any AI based system, you want top
quality across the entire set of components that are AI
powered.
In particular for retrieval, you want great ranking, great relevance,
great content understanding.
So that's what we are aiming for.
So before we go into the details, we said we
want it to be easy to get started.
So let's let's actually test that out first.
So I'm here in Foundry and we'll, we'll go back
and forth between a few different developer surface areas so
you can get a flavor of all of them.
But I'm going to start in Foundry.
So I'm going to go to build.
I have a, a foundry project already created.
And what I'll do is I'll go to knowledge.
Oh, I'm sorry, this is very small.
Hopefully that's a little better.
So, so this is the, the part of Foundry where
you manage all your knowledge bases.
So what I'll do is I'll create a new knowledge
base and we said easy.
So let's just take an easy case where we just
have a bunch of files and we want to make
it the way you do.
You would do it in a chat application today where
you can drag and drop some files and ask some
questions.
If you want to build your own version of that,
it's kind of the same thing.
You can now just say, hey, my data is just
in files, and I'm going to give this kind of
knowledge source a name.
I have a few files about movies, so I'm going
to call it Movies Wiki because I took them from
Wikipedia, and I'm going to describe what this what this
does.
So the agents know.
So I'll say use for, or rather will say full
articles about movies.
Yeah.
So there are microphones in the back, but yeah, I'll.
I'll speak up.
And I think folks turned it up.
Thank you.
All right, So what I'll do is I'm going to
grab some files.
I'm going to just drop them here.
These are kind of just movies, like articles for movies
I took from Wikipedia and I'm going to go hit
save on this.
So now I have like a knowledge base and this
knowledge base I'm going to grab the name.
This knowledge base lives in the in a particular Foundry
IQ instance I already created called here Demo 3.
So if I want to use it, I could go
call APIs to go consume this or out-of-the-box, every one
of these knowledge bases is an MCP server that I
don't have to really do anything to to to kind
of stand up or run.
So, you know, because I'm being a little lazy, instead
of writing a new agent, I'm going to use GitHub
copilot as my agent.
So here I'm interested in a new GitHub copilot session.
What I'll do is I'll say MCP to see what
I have configured.
I'm going to add a new MCP server.
I'll call it Wikipedia if I can type.
And So what I'll do is I'm going to use
an odd proxy to to connect the dots between these
two things.
And I'll say I'm going to point it to my
new MCP server.
In this case, Demo 3 was the name of my
Foundry IQ instance.
So I'll say that.
And I'll say that search.windows.net, because this is backed by
Azure Search, going to say knowledge bases.
And I'm going to paste the knowledge base we just
created.
And this is the entry point to your API.
But if you want an MCP server, you should say
slash MCP.
And you're done.
You have an MCP server right there.
And like all of our APIs, they have an API
version.
In this case, this is the API we shipped today.
So I'm going to hit save on that.
And now I have just a new MCP server connected
here that is backed by the data I just uploaded
a second ago.
Like if we go here and take a quick look,
you'll see that all the files I uploaded before are
like now, right?
They are processed and ready to go.
So once I have this if, if it works, let's
see, let's give it one more shot.
Let's see if it still does it.
All right, let's try it one more time, and if
not, I'll just use one that I already have.
OK, now it's gone.
Let's do it again.
So we said MCP Auth proxy.
We said Demo 3 was the name of our service
search thatwindows.net knowledge bases and then the name of our
knowledge base, MCP API version and brand new API version.
All right, so we'll give this a second and see
if it goes.
But the idea is once I have this, then I
can ask questions about this knowledge base if network and
everything kind of helps us.
So I know some of the movies there.
So I'm going to say which feel the Neo take.
And so now what this will do is, you know,
to answer my question, it wants to ground on on
the MCP servers that we want that we have.
So it'll go try the knowledge base I created.
It'll send a few questions, get kind of grounding information,
and then it'll say Neo took the red pill and
kind of this came from the Matrix.
So it took a minute to just go from serial
to a working knowledge base that I can connect from
my agent using MCP or using an API.
Now, of course, like this is a super simplified scenario,
but we said we wanted to make it easy to
get started and then be able to continue from there.
So the way we built Foundry IQ is to be
a comprehensive system that is layered in a way that
doesn't hide options from you.
You just choose to use whatever layer you want.
At the top, we have the Foundry integration layer where
you just saw how quickly and how productive you can
be in building new agents.
In the middle, we have a complete knowledge retrieval system
that uses agentic retrieval when needle and it'll handle things
like iterative query planning.
It handles multiple sources and chooses when to query what.
And it connects to entire Microsoft IQ surface and it
has APIs that you can use directly to connect from
there.
And in turn, that is built on this foundation of
our code retrieval engine.
Think of this as a state-of-the-art system that will do
vector retrieval, it'll do lexical search and combine the two.
It has state-of-the-art ranking models, all the things you need
to get the best quality results during ranking without having
to rebuild all of this from scratch and in the
backdrop of of enterprise grade security, quality and scale.
Now, when you use Foundry IQ, I just did a
quick pass, but if you look into the process in
detail, usually what you do is you start by provisioning
a new Foundry IQ instance.
Then you create a knowledge base like I just did.
You add some knowledge sources, and then you retrieve.
So let's walk through this process and talk about how
are we improving each of these stages to make it
easier and to be able to enable you to do
more things with it.
When it comes to provisioning, so far, Foundry IQ and
the underlying Usher AI search technology has required you to
create what we call dedicated capacity.
Dedicated capacity is great when you have a steady workload
because it's it's very predictable.
It's isolated to your to your environment, and you control
exactly what happens in there in terms of competing workloads.
On the flip side, you have to know how much
capacity you need all of that, and we want to
make this a little easier.
So I'm excited to announce the public preview of the
serverless version of Foundry IQ.
With serverless, there is no friction.
To start, it takes 1020 seconds to create a service.
The service doesn't cost anything until you actually use it.
And when you're not using it, the service scales to
0 and you only pay for the storage that your
index is used.
Serverless Foundry IQ is production ready.
You can use it for developer workloads, but you can
also use it for this very dynamic workloads, like for
example agents creating services or cases where your application may
need to create and delete services on the flight.
So you can start experimenting easy, but you can go
to production as is, and it's based on the same
state-of-the-art technology that powers the existing Foundry IQ stack.
So that means state-of-the-art ranking, instant Rag stack ready to
go and a rock solid foundation, but with all the
dynamic characteristics of serverless.
So now you have choice.
Serverless is great when you want a usage based plan,
Dedicated is great when you want a highly predictable plan
and when you look at the application patterns in general.
Serverless is great when you have lots of medium and
medium sized or small indexes, great for the developer workflow,
great for unit test where you create and delete things
on the spot, and also great for agents when you
want to let the agents create services and indexes and
whatnot on its own.
On the flip side, dedicated gives you isolated capacity and
even gives you the option to run on confidential computing
stacks top to bottom.
So to use serverless, you can do it from multiple
places.
We talked about agents and about and about people using
them.
So let's try both.
I'm going to start by, I'm going to grab a
quick prompt and I'll show you what it does in
a second.
Going to go here and paste it.
And what I'll do is I'll say, so I also
have this movie data like movie titles and whatnot from
IMDb.
So I'm going to tell my agent just go look
at that file and create a new Foundry IQ service,
create an index and load the 1st 100 rows from
that file or so.
So I'm going to let that cook for a minute,
and I'm going to show you what it looks like
to also use serverless in the other surface areas.
If I'm here in Foundry, one of the things I
can do is I, like I showed you before how
I'm using this Demo 3 service.
I can go and create a new instance or connect
to an existing one if I have one already.
But in this case, I'll say create new resource, give
it a name, a resource group.
I'm going to pick this guy.
And if you're in one of the regions that supports
serverless, like for example, let's do West Central, not that
one, let's find West central US.
Then you can choose serverless as one of these queues
in addition to all the existing ones, of course.
So I'm going to say yes to this.
Click create and you know, this will take again 10
to 20 seconds and and we'll have a new serverless
service created.
So and you know, here is like ready to use
to create knowledge bases on whatnot on it and switch
back to this and I'll forget later.
So this is what it takes to create a serverless
service Ray to go in in Foundry.
You'll find the same thing in the Azure portal.
And and if we look at this, the so this
is making progress.
So we'll let it run a little more, but at
the end we'll see that it'll be done creating everything
on its own as well.
So we'll come back to this in a second.
So once we have a Foundry IQ instance, next thing
is we got to get data to it.
So we have to create knowledge bases and bring data
from knowledge sources.
Now I mentioned knowledge bases a few times, so I
want to give you a sense of what it is.
So think of a knowledge base as the scope of
knowledge, not how we access it.
That is inside and hidden from the agent to kind
of separate concerns, but it's what, what is the domain
of knowledge and what's the policy for using that information?
So for example, you can say how much retrieval effort
you want us to take, like should we do it
a quick thing and come back or do iterative retrieval?
You can give us steering instructions to kind of influence
how the model works.
You can choose what you want us to do, answer
synthesis and whatnot.
And and then underneath this agentic retrieval stack are all
the knowledge sources where you know most of them is
typical that what we'll do is you point us at
where the knowledge is and we'll create indexes with it.
So we'll create vector and lexical indexes and whatnot.
But we also support federating out to knowledge sources that
we need to access online.
And regardless of how they are represented at runtime, we
can choose which knowledge sources to to use for any
given scenario and then go query those.
So now the question is, I should show you at
the beginning just to use a few files to ground
data.
And you know, sometimes you have an easy scenario for
that.
And by all means for easy scenarios we should do
easy things.
Now, in practice, data is all over the place.
We see sometimes you have loose files, maybe the user
gives you there in your desktop.
Sometimes the data is in an object store or in
the file on the Microsoft IQ platform or even in
other applications.
So we offered like a spectrum of options.
So in all these cases, you don't have to reinvent
all the plumbing to go through this.
So first, one of the things you can do is
you can use just files.
The thing with files is, you know, one of the
things we learned, we all learned using coding agents is
how good coding agents are at local file access.
And that works great if you have, I don't know,
maybe 50 or 100 files and a few megs worth
of content.
But I'm surprised how often I'm talking to developers and
they're like, look, I have a million PDFs in this
BLOB storage account.
What what do I do?
You can certainly not grab your way through a million
PDFs, not if you want to issue, you know, 1020
queries in a second just to try different angles to
get the data.
So we have this file knowledge source that what it
does is it allows you to just upload content.
So it's the same as files, except that it it
has the whole retrieval engine behind them that creates indexes
and that's fast retrieval.
Not only that, but when you push the files like
I did before, we'll run them through full content processing
like so.
We'll do content extraction, even we'll deal with images, we'll
vectorize the content, everything you need to do sort of
at retrieval time, things work.
Now, what we see a lot in practice is when
you have an application that manages content internally, you usually
land this content in some store, like either in BLOB
storage or in a database or in one lake if
you're using Fabric.
So we work very hard to make it easy to
connect the search tag with all of these object stores
without you having to deal with the mechanics of it.
So when you point us at say, any of these
BLOB storage, one leg and whatnot, we'll run a full
ingestion pipeline, which we'll assemble by default.
So if you don't want to think too much about
it, just point us at it.
And we'll do chunking, vectorization, all of that, and you'll
get very, quite, very high quality results.
If you want the control, you can customize every step
of it, inject your own custom steps and whatnot so
you can get exactly what you want out of it.
And while these things tend to be tax heavy, we'll
also deal with multimedia as well.
Now when we're processing these things, first step is we
look at a set of files.
You know, PDFs are a typical thing and we have
to understand what exactly is inside so we can present
it to agents.
So for that, we've integrated Foundry IQ with Azure content
understanding, which gives you like high end components for things
like optical character recognition, document layout.
You know, typical challenge is reading order is complicated and
you need to preserve it to understand the document.
Dealing with tables is in the category of life is
too short to kind of handle things like tables that
span pages, sparse tables, you know, all of these things.
So through content understanding, what we get is high quality
extraction from the additional content that then we can use
to index and then feed the the models.
So let me show you a couple of these things
in action.
So I'll come back here.
I'll go to the knowledge base I created before and
let's start by saying maybe my application uses BLOB storage
to learn content that is internally managed by by the
app itself.
Maybe it's PDFs or Markdown files or things like that.
So I'm going to say I want to use BLOB
storage.
I have like a bunch of files with notes.
I'm going to say notes, I'm going to say annotations
for movies, and I'm going to pick my storage account.
It's called Build 26.
Let's see if we find it.
There we go.
I'm going to pick my container.
I'm going to say I'm giving a system identity.
And for content extraction, I'm going to say standard, which
means use content, the full content understanding capability.
There is an embedding model already set so that we'll
do vectorization with that.
And if you want, you can give us a chat
completion model too.
And that will enable us to do image verbalization to
handle media as well.
So I'm going to just kick this off.
And once this process runs, so it'll run in the
background and it's not a one shot thing.
It will import everything now, but it'll also make it
so it runs continuously and it tracks changes.
And when things change in the source will incrementally feed
the changes into a search index.
So you automatically have a search index that is always
fresh and the Foundry IQ can use for grounding.
And now I have multiple knowledge sources here, which means
the agentic routing system can make choices about what do
you want to use what, and that's what descriptions are
for, among other things.
So just to give you a quick example, since I'm
here, let me show you a couple of examples of
content understanding.
So typical things you need to deal with this one
is a lot of PDFs actually have pictures inside like
it scans.
And in this case, this is a table that is
actually have have have written handwritten and whatnot.
And you can see that the markdown file has actual
even extracted not just the tables, but even the check
boxes.
And if you have a business looking document like that,
we'll understand the layout, we'll catch the reading order that
there is 2 columns, we'll extract the pictures and whatnot.
And sometimes you have more structured content and what you
can do is you can give us a schema of
what elements of the document you want us to extract
and we'll isolate that and extract it.
So you can fill it to to the agent or
use it as filters and things like that.
The other place where your data may be is so
far we talked about data inside the application.
And you know, a lot of what we see in
use of Foundry IQ is you have your application, you
have your own data and you want to power agents
with that.
Now that data rarely lives in isolation.
We, if you think about the data in your organization,
there's probably a bunch of, you know, Word documents and
all of your calendar and e-mail and whatnot.
It's all sitting in your M365 tenant.
And we have a work IQ that enables direct access
to that.
We also have in Fabric all your analytics state, so
all your data lake, your data warehouses, and you can
build data agents and whatnot on top.
And they found that Fabric IQ layer allows agents to
communicate with all that information in and it'll handle things
like natural language to SQL and navigating multiple data sources
and whatnot.
And then finally to access the web, we have Web
IQ that we just announced yesterday.
Now we built each of these IQ components so that
they work fine in isolation.
And if you your data is in one of these
places, please don't complicate things.
Just use the one that you need and you'll be
all set.
Now it's very common to have an agent that has
to deal with your own application data and then maybe
interact with your M365 content or your analytics structured data.
And we want to make it easy for you to
connect all these dots.
So Foundry IQ out-of-the-box supports integrating and connecting to the
entire spectrum of the IQ platform.
I'll show you a little bit more in a second
now before I go there.
The last bit of kinds of data we can connect
to is the the thing you use when the when
the built in options don't do it for you.
So if you have data in one of our supported
knowledge sources, just point us at it and we'll deal
with everything.
Now, sometimes what you have is not just data.
You have an application that you want us to connect
to and treat U.S.
data.
So we debate about what is the right interface for
this.
I kind of wish there was like AODBC for agents
or something, but there's no such a thing.
And the thing about MCP is that it's universal, like
it's not exactly meant for data integration, but it's everywhere.
And if you don't have an MCP server, it's easy
to make one.
So it became at a great integration point.
What we'll do is we'll turn the MCP output through
heuristics into like an item oriented list of things if
we can.
And then we'll even run our own ranking system on
top to improve the relevance of results.
Even at MCP, this means you can bring any data
source either of your own application or I've seen things
like for example, using the GitHub MCP server to turn
issues into one of the tables that you feed into
the system and it kind of just works.
So let me show you a couple of examples of
this.
So first I'm going to go back to the same
knowledge base.
So I'll start with work IQ.
The interesting thing about work IQ is because you just
need to point us at your tenant, there is actually
nothing to configure you just tell us that you want
us to integrate with work IQ.
Now your, your tenant admin has to give consent because
of course this is your office data.
You have to, you know, allow us to access it.
But once we have that, then it'll just work.
Now for Fabric, the interesting thing about fabric is that
Fabric has all sorts of things in it.
Like, you know, it starts with A1 lake at the
bottom where you can have all your kind of all
your but both structure files like parquet and things like
that and unstructured content.
And then you can have on top of that semantic
models and, and power VI reports and whatnot.
And then you can build data agents and even ontologies
on top of that.
So what we did in terms of integration is we
actually integrated with entire one leg catalog.
So you can see here that when I say one
layer fabric IQ, I see all sorts of objects here,
like I see lake houses, I see data agents, ontologies
and whatnot.
So I'm going to give this a name.
I'm going to say movie stats.
I'm going to say use for ratings and other stats.
And if I go real quick to my fabric instance,
this a little bigger, you can see that I have
I have in one of my lake houses.
What I have is a few parquet files that just
represent statistics about movies like ratings and yeah, things like
that.
And So what I did is I created a very
simple data agent that works on that structure data.
So I just told it what what files to to
what part K files to use.
And now I can ask questions in natural language which
fabric will turn into SQL as needed and run all
these questions.
Now if I only needed this, I cannot ask the
questions right here.
But if I'm building an knowledge base that combines the
unstructured content from one place with the structure content from
here, I want them to work together.
So what I'll do here is I'll actually, I can
just choose data agent.
And you know, in some cases, if I choose a
lake house, for example, I'll get indexing options because we'll
go index that data in the case of movies age.
In the case of this agent, there is really nothing
to index because we'll kind of integrate the questions at
retrieval time.
So I'll just say create and and now I have
a like another knowledge source, except this knowledge source will
send kind of, we'll talk agent to agent to the
data agent and then retrieve the contents and then integrate
into the rest of the retrieval workload.
All right, so let's add one more piece to this
knowledge base.
We talked about extensibility and we talked about web IQ.
Let me actually put these two things together.
So what I'll do is I'm going to use instead
of one of these data sources, I'm going to go
to browse for more.
You can see that we have more things that we
support.
And I'll say I want to use an MCP server
and I'm going to call this MCP server YYQ, maybe
Y Q2 because I already have a Web IQ used
for web search.
And then what I need here is my endpoint into
into web YQ, which I have here.
When you sign up for the Web IQ preview, you'll
get this information.
And then I need to authenticate, which I'll do here.
And last, I need to say which tool I'm going
to use, which I'll use web search.
So now I have no.
So now I have a single knowledge base that can
answer questions just like I used before.
In fact, the agent that consumes it doesn't need to
know that I added all this more importance, except now
this will use, you know, my content in Wikipedia articles
when I need that.
It'll use the web when he needs these and it'll
use fabric data agents when he needs that.
And the agentic orchestration will kind of make the choices
about what to use when go back to slides.
So one of the things that what's interesting in the
early days of kind of rag, when we all realized
you can build this kind of chat with your documents
applications is I think as an industry, we, there was
a lot of novelty and, and desire to understand how
that works.
So we took all of our documents, put them in
this thing, put a chat interface on top and we're
like here, like we can do this now.
Now here's the thing, in real world, if you look
at the documents in your company, it's not like everybody
can see every document.
And so this is, you know, document level security is
not the kind of thing you just want to improvise
real quick while you're building the rest of the stack.
So it's important that the actual retrieval system supports the
same security model than the underlying data supports.
So in Foundry IQ, we support propagating all the access
control information from sources that support access control, like say
SharePoint or you know, BLOB storage with a hierarchical namespaces
on where you can put access control lists.
And we'll propagate that into the indexes we build under
the covers.
And this is integrated with Entra.
So things like group membership works and all, like all
the things you would expect.
So at query time, you just present the credentials of
the user that is using.
So it's just the kind of the delegated token of
the user that is calling.
And based on that, it would look like the thing
you're searching only has the subset of items that that
person can see.
So security is enforced at the bottom of the stack.
You don't have to layer your own on top.
And actually same with a purview.
So if your documents have document sensitivity labels, those are
encrypted.
You can't just index them like with a random tool,
but we support integration with Purview.
So we will you know, they could them index them
and then secure them with the additional access control information
so that you can first control who can see them.
And second, you can propagate the sensitivity labels to the
UI that you are building so that you like your,
your application will look like Office from the perspective of
propagating labels and whatnot.
And we shipped a complete example for this residual there
in case you want to put kind of all these
mooring parts together now.
So first of all, let's go back to our agent,
which should be done.
So remember we kicked off that at the beginning.
I forgot to come back.
So we can see that what ended up happening is
this agent was like, yeah, got it.
I need to go provisional service.
It went created a new a new Foundry IQ service,
picked some name, give it an endpoint, create an index
and add a few files and we can actually go
check.
So if I go here, I'm going to use the
Azure portal for this, make it a little bigger.
So let's find this resource group that where we're creating
things and the name of the services FIQIMDB something something.
This is this one.
And we can see that it created a serverless service.
It created an index inside the service.
There is 100 documents there and actually we can go
inside and pick up the content and see it actually
kind of got all the movie information in here.
So I just, this was a one liner that I
told the agent and I have a working index as
a result.
So we expect, in addition to developer workflows and whatnot,
we expect this serverless Foundry IQ instances to be great
for agents that want to create their own things on
the fly and delete them later, create new ones and
so on.
All right, So we talked about creating an instance of
Foundry IQ, then we talked about putting data in it.
Now let's talk about retrieval.
So retrieval is the moment that where you're all the
work that you do actually delivers value in the end.
When it comes to retrieval or search engines, The thing
is useful, the moment you, your top 3 or 4
results are what the agent needed to ground the answer
they're looking for.
So in Foundry IQ we have an identical retrieval pipeline
that is built into the system that you can choose
to, to use.
Remember the layers of the system.
If you just want raw indexes, you can use them.
But if you want a full fully featured retrieval pipeline
that is just uses kind of an agentic method for
retrieval, it's built into a system.
Now the agentic retrieval pipeline will what, what it'll do
is it'll take the question or kind of data requirements
from the agent that is calling it.
And first thing it'll do is it'll do query planning
what it'll look at, what data sources should it go
look at and how the query should be decomposed into
parts and then go search.
It'll run a few searches and then come back, look
at the results and decide if it got what it
was hoping to get.
And if not, depending on the retrieval effort you configured,
it'll kind of iterate and they'll search again based on
the new information and then produce a final result to
show to the agent.
Now, this is something that we've been working on for
a while.
And at this point we are in kind of the
second generation of agentic retrieval with, you know, one of
the interesting things we saw is, you know, it's interesting
how from about say October of last year to now,
the models have changed significantly, including how good they are,
the things like tool calling loops and things like that.
So we significantly revamped the agentic retrieval stack to take
advantage of the latest that the language models can do.
So you can see in the charts like improvements across
the board.
So just to give you a kind of a little
bit of orientation of what these charts say is this
is a composition of multiple metrics.
In this case, how good these systems are at recall,
how often the answer is correct, how often the answer
is complete, and also how often the model says that
it doesn't know the answer even though the answer was
present in the underlying data set.
And we compare this against just lexical indexes, BM25 indexes
against hybrid search, so vector plus plus lexical systems, and
also against knowledge base with a genetic retrieval off.
We call it minimal mode, so you can see material
improvements across the entire set of metrics for all of
them.
Of course, this comes as a trade off and the
trade off is latency.
So if you use a search index, those things are
so fast that you just don't need to account for
it in your latency budget.
They are instantaneous.
Now when you call agentic retrieval, that could be a
few seconds or sometimes maybe 10 seconds or something like
that.
If you have to iterate multiple times before we get
to an answer.
Now where does this where do these improvements compared to
last iterations come from?
Well, it's a mix of things.
So first, as I said before, the agent, the language
models got better.
So our workflow for retrieval, we, we had to kind
of update significantly to fit the style of the models
that do really well today and then made a huge
difference.
Second, we trained a new semantic mode and semantic ranker.
We've been training 3 rankers for a while and we
keep being able to push the boundary on that.
Then we worked on our answer synthesis.
We have significant improvements there.
And then for some tasks like for example MCP parameter
binding, we did a lot of work to tune depending
on the model you're using, we do model specific prompt
to get it exactly right for that model because there
is enough variability between between them.
So we did the science team behind this publishes very
detailed write ups and this if you are in the
from into information retrieval or you want to understand how
we evaluate how these systems are working, I recommend checking
out that URL where you'll see a lot a lot
longer of a write up, including some of these data
you see on the screen and a lot more.
Now, in addition to that token efficiency these days is
a thing like that we all kind of think about.
So the other thing that we we looked at is,
you know, in terms of what it takes to get
a right answer, not what it takes to do a
search.
Like anybody can do a search with just a few
tokens.
The question is, did you get it right?
So what you see here is kind of like a
Pareto line of what is what is the best you
can do with the fewest possible tokens.
And again, we compare against ourselves like we compare what
is just hybrid search versus using full agentic retrieval where
you need an outer agent to orchestrate more or we
do the orchestration.
And you can see first, that we need fewer tokens
to produce better answers.
And 2nd, which is not necessarily part of this chart.
We've worked a lot in making sure that the way
we construct prompts like, you know, the way we manage
our own context is aware of how token caching caching
works to, to make sure that first, it's faster because
you, you, you hit the, the prefix cache on the
on the language model you're hitting.
And 2nd, it's cheaper because cache tokens are always cheaper
than the running full on, full on tokens.
So to give you a sense of kind of how
all of this can be put together.
So what I, what I, what I did is I
just crafted a quick, I mean craft testing vibe.
I used to say I wrote as in I wrote
the code.
I don't know what to say these days, but I
have a thing that what it does is it just
calls the retrieve API for, for the knowledge base we
just created.
And it'll show you, show us a little bit of
the internals.
So I'm going to ask you to run in medium.
So it'll run a little longer.
And I have a quick prompt that I want to,
I want to give it.
I'm going to ask to go do this.
So now, now that we have a set of moving
parts in that knowledge base, I want to go use
that knowledge base to go perform a number of tasks.
Oh, I forgot to show you this.
So now that I have multiple data sources and some
of them are actually online data sources, we can't just
create a knowledge base without telling us which model we
use for the actual orchestration, which is what I forgot
before.
So what I do here is I'll say use GPT
454 mini.
I'm going to choose a default reasoning effort.
You can override it later.
And I can also choose whether I want answer synthesis
or not.
And I can optionally give steering instructions for for both
of these things.
So now with that in place, we're going to call
retrieve again.
And so this will take a second to run, but
once it runs, I run it a little bit before.
So let me show you the output.
So in this case, you can see, you know, it
went to the ratings part.
The ratings are in.
They are this data agent that is running in Fabric
quoting this part K files in Sequel.
So you can see the results from that.
And then part of the question is how do they
do in the box office, which is not of my
data sets.
So what he did is just use the web grounding
part, went to the web, grabbed the movies that were
in the top ten.
You know, I'll leave you to decide whether or not
those are the actual best three sci-fi movies.
And and then he pulled the results and they gave
us an answer on some of them.
And some of them he was like, yeah, this was
not on the web.
Who knows why but we got a very comprehensive answer
and you can see the activity here where you know
the planner run.
Then first he went to the data agent.
I assume we went there to find what are the
top sci-fi movies.
And then he hit the MCP server for web, discarded
some of the content, the synthesis step where he constructed
an answer and then finished the reasoning process with that.
And along with this, I have all the references where
in each one of them you can see where this
data came from, what is the kind of knowledge source?
And you know, when the knowledge source gives us information,
maybe a link to the underlying file and whatnot, we'll
present it here as well.
So all this information usually you won't present in the
UX, but it's great if you want to fit it
to an agent to understand the dynamic, yeah, the interaction
better.
Or you can use it for debugging as well.
Go back here and the interesting thing is all the
technology and all the science that I talked about for
improving ranking and relevance and agentic retrieval is behind that
one API.
Either they're behind that one MCP server call or behind
the retrieve call and everything else will happen under the
covers.
Now that said, a bit of a little bit coming
back to the beginning.
Like I said, the the we designed the system to
be cleanly stacked in a way that allows you to
decide what layer of the system to use at what
point in time.
One of the design tricks that was non trivial to
pull off was to make sure that even when you
pick a layer, even though you can pick layers, once
you pick one, you don't want to be stuck in
it.
You want to have the versatility to go up and
down the stack.
And that's what we've done with the Foundry IQ stack
where you can do.
Found the integration first, or you can do knowledge bases
or you can go straight to the core retrieval engine
that we built around like this is on on Azure
AI search and you can go up and down the
stack as you need or you can change your mind
once you build 1 and I wanted to show you
a few examples of that so remember that we built
this knowledge base here.
This is the kind of funky name that we got.
And then we built some knowledge sources that are remote
and some knowledge sources that have indexed content.
So let's actually peek into what's happening under the covers.
So I'm going to just go to Azure in the
Azure portal and let me switch back to the resource
group that has particular service.
And remember, this service was called MO Three.
And 1st, I can find the knowledge base we created
there right here in the Azure Search Blade.
So this is the one we just used.
We can see all the knowledge sources, but if I
pick a little more, remember 2 of them were actually
indexed content.
So I can see the actual indexer.
This is a job that does all the transformation.
It's effectively the data pipeline that pulls data into the
index.
I can look at the runs, I can kind of
configure the internals and whatnot and actually go in and
look at the index.
For example, this was the the this one was the
the one the index that we created when we got
all the files with the articles.
And if, if I want, I can look at the
schema where I can see what is the construction of
the index.
I can even pick up things like you may have,
you may not care and then we'll choose reasonable defaults.
Or you may have very specific comparisons like or opinions
like.
For example, here is like what is the vector search
compression options where by default we do 8 bit quantization.
But you may want a different quantization policy or a
different kind of re ranking policy or things like that.
And you can control all this all the way to
details like this.
And you can also look at the actual data, like
for example here, if I pull the content of this
index, I mean, I could, I could also search, but
you can see these are the content.
This is the actual snippet that was a result of
chunking.
And I can see the actual vector here, which of
course is not very useful to look at it.
But is this the vector we use when we're computing
kind of vector differences for vector search?
Not only you have the control to do this, but
this also allows you to make choices about things like
latency trade-offs where you can do fully genetic retrieval and
it'll take a few seconds, but it'll give you great
results.
And maybe in other cases you are like, well, I
want to do something like sort of what you do
with files where you just issue a whole bunch of
searches and you want real quick results so you can
iterate on them.
And that can happen really, really fast.
I guess to give you like a last example of
these, let me show you one last thing, which is
just to give you a sense of the difference in
speed of these things.
So what I'll do is I have this other service
where instead of those 345 files I showed you before,
I took all of Wikipedia in English Wikipedia, chunked it
up and put it in an index.
So this has about 22 or so million chunks.
So it's a sizable index at this point.
And then I just wrote a simple client to so
we can kind of hit that endpoint.
So if I, if I search for simple things, we're
talking about Neo before and peel.
Like you can see this thing searches at the speed
that I can type.
In fact, I can't force the lag like I can
say Microsoft build if I didn't have any typos.
So this is searching on every crystal keystroke and I
still can't keep up.
So if you want an agent to say issue 10
searches or issue multiple rounds of 10/20 searches each, all
of them will finish well within the second all together
in parallel, which means you can could completely change the
way you think about retrieval.
You can get us to run your agentic retrieval loop
for you, or you can give us give the agent
these entry points and let them hit the the search
index as hard as you want and it'll be just
fine.
I even at 10s or hundreds of millions of documents
like in the example here.
So with that, this is all I wanted to share
with you today.
This is everything I showed you today.
You can use today.
So you can go to Foundry or the Azure Portal
or get our SD KS and get going with this.
And here's a bunch of other things that are going
on at Build that are related to the topic I
talked about.
Hope this information was useful to you all and thank
you very much for coming here this morning.